Guide to the H. Paul Castleberry Papers 1940-1983
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
H. Paul Castleberry Papers
1940-1983
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 553
Castleberry, H. Paul
22.5 Linear feet of shelf space 23 Boxes
The papers of Washington State University Political Science Professor and Department Chair, H. Paul Castleberry. Materials are concerned with teaching of political science, and with research on international affairs, world politics, the foreign policy of the United States, politics and government in the Middle East, the Vietnam War, professional associations for political science, and to Castleberry's service on the Eastern Washington Area Agency for Aging.
Professor H. Paul Castleberry was born on June 8, 1921, in Duncan, Oklahoma. He graduated with honors from Texas Tech University in 1941 and received his Masters of Arts Degree the following year, also at Texas Tech. In 1949 he was awarded the Ph.D. in Political Science from the University of Chicago. In 1945-1946 and 1946-1947 he was a Hillman Fellow. Upon graduation he became an Assistant Professor at Washington State University, in which position he served until 1954. He was an associate professor from 1954 until 1960, and became a full professor in 1960. He served as acting chairman of the Political Science Department in 1957 and from 1961-1962, and as full chairman from 1964 until 1968. Professor Castleberry taught courses in American Government, International Law, International Organization and Administration American Diplomacy, and a seminar in U.S. Foreign Policy in the Middle East. He was Fulbright lecturer at the American University in Cairo in 1953-1954 and from 1954-1955 and Fulbright lecturer at Ankara University in 1962. He is the co-author of American National Government and of American State and Local Government, and the author of numerous articles on the Middle East. Professor Castleberry is a member of the American Political Science Association, the Midwest Political Science Association, and the American Society of Public Administration, Pi Sigma Kappa and also served on the Washington Constitutional Advisory Commission for several years in the 1970's and 1980's he acted as chairman of the Whitman County Democratic Party. In 1983 he retired, but continued active in local and state Democratic politics and campus activities.
The papers of Washington State University Political Science Professor and Department Chair, H. Paul Castleberry. Materials are concerned with teaching of political science, and with research on international affairs, world politics, the foreign policy of the United States, politics and government in the Middle East, the Vietnam War, professional associations for political science, and to Castleberry's service on the Eastern Washington Area Agency for Aging.
The first four series are comprised of materials donated in the 1980s. Correspondence make up the first series, subdivided with foreign and domestic foci. The second series is a large body of material concerned with various facets of the War in Vietnam. The third and fourth series deal with public issues and politics in the State of Washington and matters concerning Washington State University, respectively.
The remaining seven series are materials donated in 1990 and are each based on some general area of the discipline of Political Science, and reflecting his research interests and teaching duties: Series 5: American government; Series 6: Correspondence; Series 7: Eastern Washington Area Agency for Aging; Series 8: International Law and Organization; International Relations; Series 9: Middle East; Series 10: United States Foreign Policy; Series 11: Tape Recordings of Speakers and Lecturers.
The initial 1980s accessions of papers were organized informally when received by the Washington State University Libraries into four main series. The 1990 accession is kept in Castleberry's original arrangement. These seven series have been placed, in alphabetical sequence, following the original four series.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The papers were gifted to the Washington State University Libraries by Mr. Castleberry in 1984 (MS 84-11), with a small addenda in 1987 (MS 87-02). A second installment of papers of H. Paul Castleberry were donated by Professor Castleberry in 1990 (MS 90-27).
Eastern Washington Area Agency on Aging Records, 1983-1984 (Cage 577)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Castleberry, H. Paul -- Archives
Washington State University -- Faculty -- Archives; Eastern Washington Area Agency on Aging -- Records and correspondence
Middle East -- Politics and government
Political science -- Study and teaching; World politics; Vietnam War, 1961-1975
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; Politics and Politicians; International Relations
- Series 1: H. Paul Castleberry Correspondence
  - Subseries 1.1: Domestic
    - American Political Science Association, 1967; 76 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Case Book in International Law, 1940; 74 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Case Book in International Law, Part Two, 1940; 81 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Civil Defense Seminar, 1981; 36 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gonzaga University Symposium on Law and the Environment, 1974; 26 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - H. Paul Castleberry, Text Correspondence, 1970; 26 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Instructional Methods, 1956-1960; 50 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Military: Role of Reserve Officer Training Corps, Speeches, 1965, 1970; 27 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1973-1977; 55 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1973-1978; 50 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1977; 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Budget and Salaries, 1977; 22 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Grant Proposal Review, 1980; 82 items. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Grant Reviews, 1980; 73 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Grant Reviews and Budget, 1980; 68 items. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Meetings, 1973; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Pacific Northwest Political Science Association, 1956-1960; 45 items. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Pacific Northwest Political Science Association, 1964-1978; 54 items. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Pacific Northwest Political Science Association, 1978-1983; 63 items. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Peace Corps, 1962; 54 items. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Peace Corps, 1962; 44 items. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Peace Corps, 1962; 41 items. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Peace Corps, 1962; 47 items. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Peace Corps, 1962; 50 items. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Peace Corps, Turkey, 1963; 32 items. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Peace Corps, Turkey, 1964-1965; 36 items. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Peace Corps, Turkey, 1965; 30 items. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Peace Corps, Turkey, 1965; 27 items. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Personal Resumes, H. Paul Castleberry, 1978; 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Political Science Association, Executive Council, 1966-1968; 50 items. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Political Science Association, National, 1965-1978; 67 items. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Speech: International Action Begins At Home, 1964; 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Speeches of H. Paul Castleberry, 1950-1960; 77 items. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Texas Tech, 1969-1970; 26 items. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - United States State Department, United Nations Conference, 1967; 27 items. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - University of Puget Sound, 1977; 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Western Political Science Association, 1961-1969; 63 items. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Western Political Science Association, 1969; 63 items. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Western Political Science Association, 1969-1977; 41 items. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Western Political Science Association, 1969-1977; 56 items. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Western Political Science Association, Constitutional Revision, 1970-1976; 76 items. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Western Political Science Association, Constitutional Revision, 1971-1972; 81 items. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Western Political Science Association, Constitutional Revision, 1971-1972; 44 items. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Western Political Science Association, Constitutional Revision, 1971-1972; 26 items. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Western Political Science Association, Constitutional Revision by-laws, 1976-1977; 41 items. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Western Political Science Association, Constitution By-Laws, 1976-1977; 43 items. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Western Political Science Association, Constitution Texts and Memos, 1976-1977; 54 items. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Western Political Science Association, Annual Conventions, 1968-1980; 9 items. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Western Political Science Association, Annual Meetings Handbook, 1968-1980; 9 items. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Western Political Science Association, Annual Meetings Handbook, 1977-1982; 45 items. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Subseries 1.2: Foreign
    - Britain- Clippings, 1970; 36 items. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Britain- Election, 1970; 26 items. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - British Government Course Notes, 1970; 80 items. (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Egypt, 1957; 32 items. (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Egypt: Nasser, Dulles, and Aswan, 1957; 44 items. (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Egypt, 1958; 27 items. (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Egypt: Notes for Walter Sharp's Field Administration In the United Nations System, 1961; 36 items. (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Foreign Service, 1961; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Interviews with Arab Leaders, 1955; 26 items. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Interviews with Some Eighty Arab Leaders in Five States on United States Foreign Policy, 1954-1955; 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Iraq, 1956; 50 items. (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Iraq, 1958; 26 items. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Jordan: American Policy and the Arabs, 1953; 67 items. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Jordan, Political Parties, 1957; 23 items. (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Jordan, undated; 20 items. (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Laos, 1961-1975; 23 items. (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Lebanon: Press, 1957; 18 items. (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Lebanon News, 1958; 27 items. (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Lebanon, 1959; 81 items. (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - London, Rules and Terms, 1970; 23 items. (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - London, Visiting Lectures, 1970; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - London, H. Paul Castleberry's Report, 1970; 21 items. (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Paris, Study Abroad, 1966; 76 items. (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Southeast Asia, 1955-1966; 16 items. (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Syria, Political Parties, 1955; 32 items. (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Syria, 1958; 18 items. (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Syria, 1955; 54 items. (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Syria, Press, undated; 20 items. (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Study Abroad, Independent, 1963-1975; 8 items. (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Series 2: Vietnam
  - Vietnam, 1962-1966; 90 items. (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Vietnam, 1962-1966; 93 items. (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Vietnam: Articles by General James Gavin and by Walter Lippmann, 1966; 32 items. (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Vietnam, 1967; 27 items. (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Vietnam, 1967; 54 items. (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Vietnam, 1967; 76 items. (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Vietnam: Notes for Speeches; J.K. Galbraith, General Shoup, 1967; 27 items. (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Vietnam: Speeches, 1967-1968; 81 items. (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Vietnam, 1968; 26 items. (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Vietnam, 1968; 90 items. (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Vietnam: Paris Talks; Walter Lippmann's Analysis, 1968; 45 items. (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Vietnam, 1968; 47 items. (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Vietnam, Tonkin Gulf Resolution Hearings, 1968-1971; 26 items. (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Vietnam, 1969; 36 items. (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Vietnam, Nixon Troop Withdrawal; Oriana Fallaci Interview with General Giap, 1969; 36 items. (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Vietnam, 1970; 34 items. (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Vietnam, 1970; 26 items. (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Vietnam, 1971; 23 items. (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Vietnam, 1972; 54 items. (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Vietnam, 1972; 36 items. (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Vietnam, 1973; 54 items. (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Vietnam, Cease-Fire, 1973; 45 items. (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Vietnam, 1974-1977; 36 items. (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Vietnam. Costs in Men and Money, 1974-1977; 26 items. (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Vietnam. Henry Kissinger's "Summing Up" Speech, January 10, 1977; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Vietnam, Scholarship and Controversy, 1975; 27 items. (Box 3, Folder 104)
- Series 3: Washington State Correspondence
  - Constitutional Advisory Council, 1965-1966; 40 items. (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Constitutional Advisory Council Meeting, 1965-1966; 67 items. (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Constitutional Advisory Council, 1966-1967; 76 items. (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Constitutional Advisory Council Report, Implementation, 1967; 16 items. (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Constitutional Revision Attempts, 1934, 1966, 1969; 4 items. (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Constitutional Revision Attempts Commission, 1968; 10 items. (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Constitutional Revision Attempts Documents, 1961-1965; 32 items. (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Constitutional Revision Attempts Documents, 1966-1967; 27 items. (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Constitutional Revision Attempts Documents, 1966-1967; 36 items. (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Chapman College Extension, Evaluation of Elmendorf Air Force Base, Anchorage, Alaska, 1979; 90 items. (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Chapman College Extension, Evaluation of Elmendorf Air Force Base, Anchorage, Alaska Continuation, 1979; 63 items. (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Colegio Cesar Chavez vs. Northwest Association of Schools and Colleges, 1977; 98 items. (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Colegio Cesar Chavez vs. Northwest Association of Schools and Colleges Continuation, 1977; 80 items. (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Colegio Cesar Chavez vs. Northwest Association of Schools and Colleges Continuation, 1977; 45 items. (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Colegio Cesar Chavez vs. Northwest Association of Schools and Colleges Continuation, 1977; 99 items. (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Elmendorf Air Force Base Program, 1978; 32 items. (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Evaluation of Okinawa Extension Programs, 1978; 67 items. (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Evaluation of Okinawa Extension Programs of the University of Maryland, 1976-1979; 18 items. (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Okinawa, University Programs, 1979; 75 items. (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, University of Maryland Overseas Programs, 1979-1980; 50 items. (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Annual Meeting, 1982
    - Part 1, 1982; 67 items. (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Part 2, 1982; 81 items. (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Part 3, 1982; 80 items. (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Part 4, 1982; 76 items. (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Part 5, 1982; 62 items. (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Part 6, 1982; 66 items. (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Summary, 1982; 80 items. (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Summary, 1982; 79 items. (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Summary, 1982; 82 items. (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Summary, 1982; 90 items. (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Northwest Commission on Colleges, Annual Meeting, 1983
    - Part 1, 1983; 63 items. (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Part 2, 1983; 67 items. (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Part 3, 1983; 66 items. (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Part 4, 1983; 80 items. (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Part 5, 1983; 27 items. (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Part 6, 1983; 74 items. (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Part 7, 1983; 83 items. (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Part 8, 1983; 36 items. (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Part 9, 1983; 32 items. (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Part 10, 1983; 84 items. (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Part 11, 1983; 38 items. (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Part 12, 1983; 30 items. (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Part 13, 1983; 78 items. (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Pierce County Democratic Convention, Proposed Rules, 1968; 36 items. (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities, 1973-1976; 44 items. (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities, 1973-1978; 20 items. (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities. Part 2, 1973-1978; 66 items. (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities. Part 3, 1973-1978; 12 items. (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities. Part 4, 1973-1978; 48 items. (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities. Part 5, 1973-1978; 78 items. (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities, 1977-1978; 76 items. (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Washington Commission for the Humanities. Part 2, 1977-1978; 80 items. (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Washington State Humanities Program, Vol. I, 1979-1980; 99 items. (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Washington State Humanities Program, Vol. I Continuation, 1979-1980; 98 items. (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Washington State Humanities Program, Volume II, 1979-1980; 116 items. (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Washington State Humanities Program, Volume II Continuation, 1979-1980; 114 items. (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Lobbying Packet, 1979-1980; 28 items. (Box 4, Folder 161)
- Series 4: Washington State University Correspondence
  - Administration: President Glen Terrell, 1968-1972; 16 items. (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1959-1983; 16 items. (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - Budget Committee, 1981; 76 items. (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Budget Committee, 1981; 77 items. (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Budget Committee, 1980-1983; 81 items. (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - Council on Higher Education, 1973; 76 items. (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Economic and Military Aid Seminar, 1972; 44 items. (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Educational Policies Calendar, 1967-1972; 67 items. (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Edward R. Murrow Symposium, "The International Rights of Media News Flow, 1979", 54 items. (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Academic Rank, 1971-1972; 27 items. (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Agenda, 1972-1973; 23 items. (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Balloting for Department Chairmen, 1972-1973; 36 items. (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Collective Bargaining, 1972-1973; 76 items. (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Collective Bargaining, Collective Bargaining, 1973-1974; 66 items. (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1976-1980; 54 items. (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1976-1983; 84 items. (Box 4, Folder 177)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Deans, 1980-1983; 80 items. (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Financial Exigency, 1982; 80 items. (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1982; 32 items. (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1982; 36 items. (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Minutes, 1975; 18 items. (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Miscellaneous, 1971-1975; 66 items. (Box 4, Folder 183)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1972-1973; 27 items. (Box 4, Folder 184)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1972-1973; 36 items. (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1972-1973; 50 items. (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1972-1973; 68 items. (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Resume of Henry A. Turner, 1979; 8 items. (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Retirement, 1972; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Revision of Faculty Manual, 1972; 7 items. (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, Sabbatical, 1972; 79 items. (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1973; 57 items. (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1973; 50 items. (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1980; 67 items. (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1981-1982; 63 items. (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1981-1982; 45 items. (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1981-1983; 54 items. (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1982-1983; 76 items. (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1982-1983; 58 items. (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1983; 81 items. (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Faculty Council; Government Relations Committee, 1974-1975; 47 items. (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Faculty Council, 1976-1977; 26 items. (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Faculty Evaluation, 1950-1959; 21 items. (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, 1967-1981; 23 items. (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, 1967-1981; 36 items. (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, Confidentiality of Student Records, 1968; 27 items. (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, Student Bill of Rights, 1968-1969; 63 items. (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, 1968-1970; 40 items. (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, 1968-1970; 26 items. (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, 1968-1970; 44 items. (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, Strike, 1970; 32 items. (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, Strike, 1970; 36 items. (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, Strike, 1970; 54 items. (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - General Education, 1973; 57 items. (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - General Education, 1964-1969; 84 items. (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Graduate Programs, 1967; 5 items. (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Honors Program, 1963-1969; 41 items. (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - International Affairs: State College of Washington Final Report of the World Affairs Committee, June, 1953; 96 items. (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Law School Admissions, 1971-1976; 45 items. (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Law School Admissions, 1963-1980; 67 items. (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Model United Nations, 1979-1980; 50 items. (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - National Honor Scholarships for the University of Chicago Law School, 1967-1971; 32 items. (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Political Science Department Staff Meetings, 1980- 1981; 50 items. (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Political Science Graduate Theses, 1981; 41 items. (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Political Science Theses Proposals, 1977-1982; 36 items. (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - Pre-Law Option: Poltical Science or English?, 1977- 1979; 27 items. (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Sperry and Hutchinson Lectureship Program. Alfred M. Lilienthal Lecture, 1964-1970; 32 items. (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Continuation, 1964-1970; 26 items. (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Steering Committee, 1982-1983; 76 items. (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - Steering Committee, 1982-1983; 57 items. (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Steering Committee, 1982-1983; 63 items. (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Steering Committee, 1982-1983; 41 items. (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Steering Committee, 1982-1983; 45 items. (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Steering Committee, 1982-1983; 54 items. (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Steering Committee, 1982-1983; 50 items. (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - University Chapter of Omnicron Delta Kappa, 1969-1976; 8 items. (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - University Policy: Cheating and Plagiarism, 1961-1980; 8 items. (Box 5, Folder 237)